James Kenneth Seconde, BA

07738066610 Birmingham, UK @secondej linkedin.com/in/secondej jim@thefusionhub.com https://devtheatre.net

PERSONAL STATEMENT

An experienced Developer Advocate looking for a new role. After spending 10 years doing technical management in a theatre whilst simultaneously starting a tech career in business intelligence, I moved into backend web development. I am now a passionate advocate for developers and tech culture. With a dissertation in standup comedy theory and knowledge of web development/cloud/analytics, I am well placed to promote your product, write technical documentation and to build a community that uses and feeds back to its owners/maintainers.

COMPETENCIES

Community & Speaking

Created PHP usergroup for city as it was absent. Joined meetup/conference Fusion as organizer and host to grow the brand and bring in international Developer Advocate speakers. Created a board of peers to oversee and grow the tech ecosystem in the city. Free consultant to new developers looking for contacts or to start their careers in development. Currently on tour in the UK speaking, regular conference delegate in the UK.

Software Development

4 years experience in both large-scaled (Symfony) and microserviced (Laravel) PHP frameworks. 10 years SQL experience. Vue and React for frontend work in JS., Node for command line tool authoring. Experience in various other regular supporting technologies such as REST, SOAP, Apache Solr, GraphQL, MariaDB.

DevOps

Currently AWS architecture ops such as EC2, Aurora, Cloudwatch, S3, Laravel Forge. Experience in various deployment pipeline tooling such as Jenkins, Docker, Bitbucket, Github, Gitlab, Papertrail, Loggly.

Documentation & Process

4 years experience delivering handover documentation in Markdown, technical documentation for agency clients & users, technical blog articles for current employer. Currently using notion.so for internal docs, previously extensive use of JIRA, Trello, Asana and Basecamp for client communication or sprint organisation and/or Scrum planning/standups/retrospectives.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Developer Advocate, EastsideCo, 2018-present, Birmingham

- Created Developer Relations project, transforming company tooling in preparation for release
- Maintenance of open source libraries
- Microservices in AWS, Laravel, Vue.js

Co-Organiser/Host, Fusion Meetup, 2018-present, Birmingham

Host & Coach, Codebar Birmingham, 2018-present, Birmingham

Hosting a regular group for minorities to break into coding using mentor tutorship

Creator/Host/Speaker, brumPHP, 2017-present, Birmingham

· Networking with and being a part of the global PHP usergroup community

Software Engineer, Bluetel, 2017-2018, Birmingham

• Full stack for large project with major international journalism organisation

Software Engineer, CampaignAmp, 2016-2017 London/Remote

Product development in music industry extensively using Spotify's API for major international film studio using Symfony

Technical Manager, Rosemary Branch Theatre, 2011-2016, London

Lighting designs, sound design, stage management with sole responsibility for theatre's resources

Data Analyst, Registry Trust Limited, 2007-2016, London

• Technical documentation, data analysis, authored automated statistics system to refactor years of legacy systems

EDUCATION

2005 - 2007, BA (Hons) Theatre Studies, Communication & English Theatre 2:1, University of Chester

1997 - 2002, 3 A2 Level (BBC), 9 GCSE(A-C), Repton School

PERSONAL

Being a vinyl collector since 1999 has seen me DJ over the years. Enthusiast for independent board games, independent video games and a flair for admittedly average international cooking.